<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PyDistrict (Posts about meetup)</title><link>https://pydistrict.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://pydistrict.org/categories/meetup.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2025 PyDistrict </copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 19:28:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>February Dojo</title><link>https://pydistrict.org/posts/2025/01/2025-feb-dojo.html</link><dc:creator>PyDistrict</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;A new year, a new Dojo -- join us for an evening of Python, food, and silly
mistakes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;DC Python Dojo&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us for an evening of Python coding, food, and silly mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way it works is fairly simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6:30 - Everyone votes on a project to work on for the evening&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​6:45 - We break up into small groups to work on the problem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​7:45 - Everyone comes back together for show &amp;amp; tell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​8:00 - We adjourn to a local establishment to discuss what went right over beverages&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>meetup</category><guid>https://pydistrict.org/posts/2025/01/2025-feb-dojo.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 18:46:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>March Meetup</title><link>https://pydistrict.org/posts/2022/03/march-meetup-2022.html</link><dc:creator>PyDistrict</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Let's kick off 2022!! Join us for our March meetup. We're going to keep it
informal and have a few great discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;PyCon 2022 Preview&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://pycon.us/"&gt;PyCon 2022&lt;/a&gt; is coming up on April 29th in Salt Lake City.
Come find out what to expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Functional Programming in Python&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vic Kumar&lt;/strong&gt; will present an overview of &lt;a href="https://us.pycon.org/2022/schedule/presentation/80/"&gt;the talk he'll be giving at PyCon 2022
on Saturday, April 30th&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>meetup</category><guid>https://pydistrict.org/posts/2022/03/march-meetup-2022.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 22:46:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>November Meetup - Behavior Driven Development</title><link>https://pydistrict.org/posts/2021/11/november-meetup-2021.html</link><dc:creator>PyDistrict</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for our monthly virtual PyDistrict. We'll have one great speaker who'll
be presenting: &lt;strong&gt;Brian Sjoberg&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Brian Sjoberg - Let's Make Sure Our Product Behaves Like What the Customers Need&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever heard the words, “That is not what I asked for?”
Have you struggled with understanding the real needs of the user?
Would you like to deliver a high-quality product that meets the user needs?
If you answered yes to one or more of these questions then come join us for this presentation on what Behavior Driven Development is, its benefits, and how to do it in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;About Brian&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone! My name is Brian Sjoberg, I hail from sunny Florida where I earned my Computer Engineering degree from the University of South Florida. Go Bulls!! I am a former eXtreme Programming (XP) Java developer, turned Project Manager, turned Program Manager, turned Agile/Lean Coach. I have been living on the front lines of implementing Scrum, Kanban, and engineering practices for the past 14 years with multiple teams. I have coached both in the commercial and government space. I am fueled with a passion to help individuals, teams, and organizations frequently deliver high quality products at a sustainable pace that customers LOVE!! I love sharing what I have learned during my professional journey and have presented at the national and local level on many topics related to Agility.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>meetup</category><guid>https://pydistrict.org/posts/2021/11/november-meetup-2021.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 14:17:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>September Meetup - Macro Keyboards with CircuitPython</title><link>https://pydistrict.org/posts/2021/09/september-meetup-2021.html</link><dc:creator>PyDistrict</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for our monthly virtual PyDistrict. We'll have one great speaker who'll
be presenting: &lt;strong&gt;Kevin Harris&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Kevin Harris - Macro Keyboards with CircuitPython&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process from designing to creating mechanical macro keyboards, including
CAD, wiring, soldering, and coding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;About Kevin&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kevin Harris is a senior at Wilson High School in DC. He's on the robotics team
and plans to study engineering in college.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>meetup</category><guid>https://pydistrict.org/posts/2021/09/september-meetup-2021.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 21:49:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>June Meetup - Authorization using Python + SQLAlchemy</title><link>https://pydistrict.org/posts/2021/06/june-meetup-2021.html</link><dc:creator>PyDistrict</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for our monthly virtual PyDistrict. We'll have one great speaker who'll
be presenting: &lt;strong&gt;Sam Scott&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Sam Scott - Adding Structure to a Sea of Chaos: A principled approach to authorization using Python + SQLAlchemy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authorization is an unstructured problem. Writing code to decide who can do
what in your app can cover a broad set of cases. The most structure that
typically gets applied to this problem area is a set of if statements and
roles, but in reality, there are a lot more patterns and structure that we can
apply. &lt;a href="https://www.osohq.com"&gt;Oso&lt;/a&gt; is an open source batteries-included
library for building authorization in your application. It's a bit like
SQLAlchemy in that it provides a structured approach to authorization, much
like SQLAlchemy does for data modeling and access. In this talk, we'll provide
a mental model for authorization and show how to apply it using oso, Python and
SQLAlchemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;About Sam&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sam Scott is the cofounder and CTO of &lt;a href="https://www.osohq.com"&gt;Oso&lt;/a&gt;. He’s
received a PhD in Cryptography, is an engineer by training, and can discuss
anything from authorization and security patterns in SQLAlchemy, to how oso
works under the hood and interfaces with Python via FFI, to trends in security
policy-as-code and his contributions to TLS 1.3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find him on Twitter &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/samososos"&gt;@samososos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>meetup</category><guid>https://pydistrict.org/posts/2021/06/june-meetup-2021.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 21:49:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>May Meetup - Probabilistic Programming using PyStan</title><link>https://pydistrict.org/posts/2021/05/may-meetup-2021.html</link><dc:creator>PyDistrict</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for our monthly virtual PyDistrict. We'll have one great speaker who'll
be presenting: &lt;strong&gt;Saran Ahluwalia&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Saran Ahluwalia - Probabilistic Programming using PyStan: Quantifying the business impact of adverse events on networks using device telemetry&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Causal Inference has been greatly popularized in the past several years in both
contemporary machine learning and in statistics. Applications include
advertising campaigns, economic analysis and disaster recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what exactly is "causal inference"? From a statistician's perspective, it
is the study of the consequences of the effects of individuals' actions. This
is really important as one causal phenomena in your data can be more meaningful
than dozens of correlation patterns in your data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will briefly discuss an application of causal inference to
cybersecurity. Objectives in this talk include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An introduction to Bayesian structural time series models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An introduction to probabilistic programming using Stan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to construct hierarchical models that can capture more complex dynamics
   of systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An introduction to network traffic analysis and its utility in impacting
   both cybersecurity and the science of causal inference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;About Saran&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saran Ahluwalia is currently a Data Scientist working within the Advanced
Security Initiatives group in Cisco. &lt;a href="https://ahlusar1989.github.io/"&gt;You can learn more about Saran
here&lt;/a&gt;. You can also follow him and his
ramblings on 1990s and 2000-era NBA basketball, COVID-19 policy and statistics
(among other topics) on Twitter:
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SaranAhluwalia"&gt;@SaranAhluwalia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>meetup</category><guid>https://pydistrict.org/posts/2021/05/may-meetup-2021.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 01:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>April Meetup</title><link>https://pydistrict.org/posts/2021/04/april-meetup-2021.html</link><dc:creator>PyDistrict</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for our monthly virtual PyDistrict. We'll have one great speaker who'll
be presenting: &lt;strong&gt;Taylor Bird&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Taylor Bird -  Blueprints for a Serpent&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A survey of Python variants. Let's discuss that Python is a specification for a
language of which cPython is just the most popular reference implementation.
We'll talk at a high level about how this is possible and then we'll cover some
examples of alternate implementations of Python, what they offer and why you
might want to use them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;About Taylor&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taylor Bird software developer with Excella. He has roughly a decade long
background in Java programming and software design for enterprise systems. His
recent focus has been on data science, and he is mostly programming in Python
these days for that.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>meetup</category><guid>https://pydistrict.org/posts/2021/04/april-meetup-2021.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Early April Lightning Talks</title><link>https://pydistrict.org/posts/2021/04/early-april-lightning-talks.html</link><dc:creator>PyDistrict</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;It's an April two-fer! Join us for an evening of lightning talks. If you're
interested in presenting, please reach out to the organizers on
&lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/pydistrict"&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href="http://www.dctechslack.com/"&gt;DC Tech
Slack's&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;#pydistrict&lt;/code&gt; channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Jim Taysom - Manage your Python environments with Pipenv&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pipenv combines virtual environments and package installation tools to make a
simple workflow for having a consistent package installation experience. &lt;a href="https://xkcd.com/1987/"&gt;This
will help prevent your computer from being declared a superfund site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Aru Sahni - Pattern Matching&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python 3.10 is on the horizon. With it comes a new feature that has the
internet abuzz - Pattern Matching. Learn why it exists, how it's used, and
more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Rami Chowdhury - Django-Ninja&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to try FastAPI? Have an existing Django app? Learn how to bring Ninja
skills to bear with Django-Ninja!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Vic Kumar - Functional Programming in Python&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever hear your overzealous friend talking about "functional programming" and
have no idea what they're talking about? We're going to try and bridge the gap
and do a few functional examples in Python.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>meetup</category><guid>https://pydistrict.org/posts/2021/04/early-april-lightning-talks.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 23:39:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>February Meetup</title><link>https://pydistrict.org/posts/2021/02/february-meetup.html</link><dc:creator>PyDistrict</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for our monthly virtual PyDistrict. We'll have one great speaker who'll
be presenting: &lt;strong&gt;Will Angel&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Will Angel - Logging and Monitoring Python Applications&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've built your Python application and deployed it! Now what? Specifically,
now what is your application doing and how do you monitor it. This talk will
cover logging and monitoring Python applications using the Python standard
library logging module and open source monitoring tools including Prometheus
and Grafana. Learn the basics and best practices of application logging, and
get an overview of the monitoring ecosystem that you can use to get better
insights into the health and utilization of your Python apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;About Will&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will Angel is a Data Scientist and Author, co-organizer for the Data
Visualization DC meetup group, and helps lead communications and development
for the Data Community DC non-profit. He has worked in consumer and healthcare
startups, and has a background in bioethics and physics. Learn more at
&lt;a href="http://www.williamangel.net"&gt;http://www.williamangel.net&lt;/a&gt; or on twitter at
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DataDrivenAngel"&gt;@DataDrivenAngel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>meetup</category><guid>https://pydistrict.org/posts/2021/02/february-meetup.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 23:20:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>October Meetup</title><link>https://pydistrict.org/posts/2020/10/october-meetup.html</link><dc:creator>PyDistrict</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for our monthly virtual PyDistrict. We'll have one great speaker who'll
be presenting: &lt;strong&gt;Ying Wang&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Ying Wang - Property Based Testing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk introduces property-based testing as a concept, and describes some
ways you can start integrating PBT into your test suite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ying is a software engineer in DC; he enjoys Chipotle burritos, sunlight, and
making computer fans spin loudly.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>meetup</category><guid>https://pydistrict.org/posts/2020/10/october-meetup.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 02:17:39 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>